<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Web3 Meta-Crisis Wiki</title>
      <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Web3 Meta-Crisis Wiki</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Auditability</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Auditability</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Auditability</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Auditability Definition and Institutional Significance Auditability represents the capacity of systems to provide comprehensive, verifiable, and independently accessible records of all operations, decisions, and resource flows that enable external verification of institutional behavior without requi... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Immutability</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Immutability</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Immutability</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Immutability Definition and Conceptual Framework Immutability represents one of the most philosophically significant properties of blockchain systems: the capacity to create records that resist alteration or deletion once committed to the distributed ledger. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Programmability</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Programmability</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Programmability</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Programmability Definition and Conceptual Significance Programmability represents the capacity to encode complex logical operations and automate rule-based processes through smart contracts and programmable blockchain systems. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Transparency</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Transparency</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Transparency</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Transparency Definition and Democratic Significance Transparency represents the capacity to make information, processes, and decisions visible, auditable, and accessible to relevant stakeholders without requiring permission from intermediary authorities. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Trustlessness</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Trustlessness</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/Trustlessness</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Trustlessness Definition and Theoretical Framework Trustlessness represents a paradigmatic shift in computational systems—the capacity to achieve reliable coordination and execution without requiring trust in any single party, intermediary, or central authority. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>censorship resistance</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/censorship-resistance</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Capacities/censorship-resistance</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Censorship Resistance Conceptual Framework and Democratic Significance Censorship resistance represents the capacity of information and communication systems to maintain functionality and provide access to data, services, and resources despite attempts by powerful entities to block, restrict, or con... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Algorithmic Amplification</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Algorithmic-Amplification</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Algorithmic-Amplification</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Algorithmic Amplification Definition and Theoretical Foundations Algorithmic Amplification represents the systematic use of computational systems to selectively increase the reach, visibility, and influence of specific content, behaviors, or social phenomena beyond their organic propagation patterns... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Behavioral Economics</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Behavioral-Economics</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Behavioral-Economics</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Behavioral Economics Definition and Theoretical Foundations Behavioral Economics represents an interdisciplinary field that integrates psychological insights about human decision-making with economic analysis, challenging the traditional assumption of perfectly rational actors to explain how cogniti... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Choice</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Choice</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Choice</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Choice Definition and Philosophical Foundations Choice represents the fundamental capacity for autonomous agency and self-determination that enables individuals and communities to shape their own conditions of existence without external coercion or systemic constraint. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Collective Action Problem</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Collective-Action-Problem</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Collective-Action-Problem</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Collective Action Problem Definition and Theoretical Foundations The Collective Action Problem represents a fundamental challenge in social coordination where rational individual behavior leads to collectively suboptimal outcomes, despite mutual benefits available through cooperation. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 22:25:01 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>