<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Web3 Meta-Crisis Wiki</title>
      <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Web3 Meta-Crisis Wiki</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Democratic Innovation</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Democratic-Innovation</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Democratic-Innovation</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Democratic Innovation Definition and Theoretical Foundations Democratic Innovation encompasses new institutional forms, processes, and technologies designed to enhance democratic participation, deliberation, and decision-making beyond traditional electoral democracy. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:45:15 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Tragedy of the Commons</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Tragedy-of-the-Commons</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Tragedy-of-the-Commons</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Tragedy of the Commons Definition and Theoretical Foundations The Tragedy of the Commons represents a foundational economic theory describing situations where individual rational behavior leads to collective irrationality and resource depletion. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:43:46 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Social Capital</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Social-Capital</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Social-Capital</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Social Capital Definition and Theoretical Foundations Social Capital represents the networks of relationships, shared norms, values, and institutional trust that enable collective action and cooperation within communities. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:42:15 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Delegated Proof of Stake</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Delegated-Proof-of-Stake</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Delegated-Proof-of-Stake</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Delegated Proof of Stake Definition and Theoretical Foundations Delegated Proof of Stake (DPoS) represents a consensus mechanism where token holders elect a small number of representatives (delegates or witnesses) who are responsible for validating transactions and producing blocks on behalf of the ... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:37:15 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Blockchain Trilemma</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Blockchain-Trilemma</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Blockchain-Trilemma</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Blockchain Trilemma Definition and Theoretical Foundations The Blockchain Trilemma represents a fundamental constraint in distributed ledger design where blockchain systems can simultaneously optimize at most two of three critical properties: security, scalability, and decentralization. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:35:47 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Collective Intelligence</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Collective-Intelligence</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Collective-Intelligence</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Collective Intelligence Definition and Theoretical Foundations Collective Intelligence represents the emergent cognitive capability that results from collaboration, communication, and coordination among multiple individuals or agents that exceeds the problem-solving capacity of any individual partic... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:34:18 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Authentication</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Authentication</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Authentication</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Authentication Definition and Theoretical Foundations Authentication represents the process of verifying the identity of users, devices, or systems attempting to access resources or perform actions, implementing what computer scientist Butler Lampson calls “identification and authentication” as the ... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:32:39 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Accountability</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Accountability</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Accountability</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Accountability Definition and Theoretical Foundations Accountability represents systematic mechanisms that enable individuals, organizations, and systems to be held responsible for their actions, decisions, and outcomes through transparent processes of oversight, evaluation, and consequence enforcem... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:28:30 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Access Control</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Access-Control</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Primitives/Access-Control</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Access Control Definition and Theoretical Foundations Access Control represents systematic mechanisms for determining which entities (users, programs, or processes) can access specific resources and what operations they can perform on those resources. ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:27:07 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Algorithmic Bias</title>
    <link>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Algorithmic-Bias</link>
    <guid>https://omniharmonic.github.io/web3metacrisiswiki/Patterns/Algorithmic-Bias</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Algorithmic Bias Definition and Theoretical Foundations Algorithmic Bias represents systematic and unfair discrimination embedded in automated decision-making systems that disproportionately affects certain groups based on protected characteristics including race, gender, age, socioeconomic status, ... ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:25:36 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>